<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geekdom on The Geeky Gear Blog</title>
    <link>http://chosancarson.github.io/geekygearblog/categories/geekdom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geekdom on The Geeky Gear Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 09:53:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://chosancarson.github.io/geekygearblog/categories/geekdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a geek?</title>
      <link>http://chosancarson.github.io/geekygearblog/2016/06/08/what-is-a-geek</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 09:53:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chosancarson.github.io/geekygearblog/2016/06/08/what-is-a-geek</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-geek-defined:21d1f83e20d00c64b72a073f2a5514c0&#34;&gt;A geek defined&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is a geek and how is it differentiated from a nerd? To begin to answer this question lets start with the definition and of the words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geek:&lt;br /&gt;
    1. An unfashionable or socially inept person.&lt;br /&gt;
    2. A carnival performer who performs disgusting or wild acts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nerd:&lt;br /&gt;
    1. A foolish or contemptible person who lacks social skills or is boringly studious&lt;br /&gt;
    2. A single-minded expert in a particular technical field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In todays world you might be hard pressed to find someone whom defines geek using the above definitions. However the definition of nerd is probably on point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-brief-history-of-geek:21d1f83e20d00c64b72a073f2a5514c0&#34;&gt;The brief History of Geek&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1900s carnival performers called geeks would do disgusting acts to attract crowds. This usually consisted of biting the heads off chickens, rats,  and snakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then sometime in the 1950s the term came to describe someone who was unsociable and freakishly devoted to some intellectual pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the 1980s and the rise of computers it was used as an insult to describe someone who was knowledgeable in technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What used to be a pejorative is now a term of endearment and pride, with most people defining a Geek as a person obsessively invested in a particular interest or hobby. Whereas nerd can still be considered a semi insult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;geek-vs-nerd:21d1f83e20d00c64b72a073f2a5514c0&#34;&gt;Geek vs Nerd&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some would argue that they are the same thing. I&amp;rsquo;d argue that they are similar in that each is characterized by obsession. Geeks can be characterized by an obsession with things and collecting, whereas as nerd would be more obsessed with academic pursuits. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a fine line for example a computer nerd would be someone that studies computer science and is into programming, where a computer geek would be described as someone who is an enthusiast and obsessed with computers and technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nerds and geeks can appear in any field, consider sports. Yes it&amp;rsquo;s true there are sport nerds as well as sport geeks. Both would share an obsession with the sport. Where they differ is where their interest leads them. The geek would be drawn to collectables and memorabilia. Think the guy that has to track down that rare hat or jersey. The nerd would be obsessed with history and stats he&amp;rsquo;s that guy that can rattle off stats from the 1920s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end its all just words and trying to define a person by such narrow terms can often be dehumanizing. When I call someone a geek all I&amp;rsquo;m really saying is yea that guy over there. He is into some really cool stuff and knows about all the leet gear. When I say nerd all it really means is that person is into some really cool stuff but on an academic level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>